<idea-plugin>
    <id>no.dervis.webbrowser</id>
    <name>Web Browser Panel</name>
    <!-- Vendor / "Additional Information" on the Marketplace & plugin details panel.
         Update the url to your own repository or homepage before publishing. -->
    <vendor email="dervis@mansuroglu.net" url="https://github.com/dervism/intellij-webbrowser">Dervis Mansuroglu</vendor>

    <!-- OVERVIEW: shown as the Marketplace "Overview" tab and the plugin description. -->
    <description><![CDATA[
        <p><b>Web Browser Panel</b> embeds a Chromium-based web browser (the IDE's
        bundled JCEF runtime) directly in a tool window, so you can preview a local
        web dev server right next to your code &mdash; no Alt&#8209;Tab required.</p>

        <p><em>Note:</em> the embedded view is plain Chromium (the IDE's bundled JCEF
        runtime), so it doesn't share your everyday browser's profile, extensions, or
        bookmarks. The <b>Open in&hellip;</b> button hands the current page to your
        system default browser, or any browser configured in the IDE.</p>

        <h3>Features</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Embedded browser tool window</b> &mdash; back / forward / reload and an editable address bar.</li>
            <li><b>Themed empty state</b> &mdash; a clean, theme-aware SVG placeholder instead of Chromium's raw error page when nothing is loaded or a site is unreachable.</li>
            <li><b>Live reload on save</b> &mdash; reload when files are saved; pick the folder and file extensions to watch.</li>
            <li><b>Timed auto-refresh</b> &mdash; reload on a fixed interval you set, in seconds.</li>
            <li><b>Open browser on run</b> &mdash; when a run configuration starts, wait until the URL is reachable, then open and navigate the tool window automatically.</li>
            <li><b>Open in&hellip;</b> &mdash; open the current page in your system default browser, or any browser configured under <b>Settings &gt; Tools &gt; Web Browsers</b>.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>Getting started</h3>
        <p>Open the <b>Web Browser</b> tool window from the right tool-window bar, then set
        your dev-server URL, live-reload, and open-on-run options under
        <b>Settings &gt; Tools &gt; Web Browser Panel</b>.</p>

        <h3>Requirements</h3>
        <p>Requires a JCEF-enabled JetBrains Runtime (the default JBR). If JCEF is
        unavailable, the tool window shows a short notice instead of a browser.</p>

        <h3>Additional information</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Author:</b> Dervis Mansuroglu</li>
            <li><b>Source code &amp; issue tracker:</b> <a href="https://github.com/dervism/intellij-webbrowser">github.com/dervism/intellij-webbrowser</a></li>
            <li><b>License:</b> MIT &mdash; free and open source.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><b>Technical details:</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li>Written in Kotlin and built with the IntelliJ Platform Gradle Plugin.</li>
            <li>Embeds Chromium via JCEF (the bundled JetBrains Runtime) &mdash; no external browser is required for the tool window.</li>
            <li>Compatible with IntelliJ IDEA 2026.1+ (since-build 261) and other JetBrains IDEs running a JCEF-enabled runtime.</li>
            <li>A lightweight platform plugin &mdash; depends only on <code>com.intellij.modules.platform</code>.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></description>

    <!-- WHAT'S NEW: shown as the Marketplace "What's New" / change-notes section. -->
    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <h3>0.5.0 – 0.5.7</h3>
        <p>The 0.5 line turns the panel into a proper in-IDE dev browser:
        in-page search, DevTools and a console, a full-featured tab strip,
        project-aware settings, and editor integration.</p>

        <p><b>Dev-loop power tools.</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Find in page</b> (Ctrl/Cmd+F) — inline find bar with
            next / previous and the standard Enter / Shift+Enter / Esc keys.</li>
            <li><b>DevTools</b> — open the full Chromium DevTools in its own
            window from a toolbar button or with F12.</li>
            <li><b>Browser console</b> — a bottom panel shows the active tab's
            <code>console.log/warn/error</code> output in real time, with
            level-coloured lines. Toggle it from the settings row or with
            <b>Ctrl+`</b>.</li>
            <li><b>Hard reload</b> bypassing the disk cache (Ctrl/Cmd+Shift+R),
            plus a <b>Stop</b> button: the reload icon turns into a stop icon
            while a page is loading and cancels the load on click.</li>
        </ul>

        <p><b>A full tab strip.</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Drag to reorder</b>, <b>pin</b> tabs, and a right-click menu
            with <i>Pin</i> / <i>Close</i> / <i>Close Other Tabs</i>. Pinned
            tabs survive <i>Close Other</i> and round-trip across restarts.</li>
            <li><b>Overflow</b> — the tab strip scrolls horizontally when there
            are more tabs than fit, instead of wrapping onto a second row.</li>
            <li><b>Reopen closed tab</b> (Ctrl/Cmd+Shift+T), <b>middle-click to
            close</b>, <b>New Tab</b> (Ctrl/Cmd+T), and <b>Ctrl+Tab</b> /
            <b>Ctrl+Shift+Tab</b> cycling.</li>
            <li><b>Persisted session</b> — your open tabs are restored when the
            project re-opens.</li>
        </ul>

        <p><b>Project-aware settings.</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Per-project home URL</b> overriding the application default,
            used by the <i>Home</i> button and <i>Open in…</i>.</li>
            <li><b>Glob watch patterns</b> — a power-user alternative to the
            folder + extensions field, e.g.
            <code>/project/src/**/*.{ts,tsx}</code>, one per line.</li>
            <li><b>Per-host zoom memory</b> — a site's zoom level is remembered
            and reapplied next time you visit that host.</li>
            <li><b>Settings validation</b> — <i>Apply</i> refuses invalid input
            (empty URL, unparseable globs) and focuses the offending field.</li>
        </ul>

        <p><b>Address bar &amp; editor integration.</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>History-backed autocomplete</b> on the address bar — a
            per-project list of visited URLs suggested as you type (arrow keys
            to navigate, Enter to accept, Esc to dismiss).</li>
            <li><b>Open URL in Web Browser Panel</b> — an editor right-click
            action (Ctrl/Cmd+Shift+B) opens the URL under the caret, or the
            selected text, in the panel instead of the OS browser.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.2.8 – 0.4.3</h3>
        <p>A series of releases focused on a richer browsing experience and a
        tidier toolbar.</p>
        <p><b>Tabs.</b> The tool window now supports multiple tabs. Open new
        tabs from the <b>New Tab</b> button, close them with the
        <code>×</code> on each tab, and links that would normally open in a
        separate window (<code>target="_blank"</code>) now open as a new tab
        inside the panel instead of escaping the IDE. Each tab keeps its own
        URL, navigation history, and zoom level; switching tabs updates the
        toolbar to match.</p>
        <p><b>Zoom.</b> A <b>Zoom ▾</b> dropdown on the toolbar offers
        <i>Zoom In</i>, <i>Zoom Out</i>, and <i>Reset Zoom</i>, with a
        matching <b>Zoom ▸</b> submenu on the right-click context menu. Zoom
        is per-tab and steps reliably in both directions.</p>
        <p><b>Compact toolbar.</b> Back, forward, and reload are now
        borderless icons that sit inside the URL field, so the address bar
        stays usable even on narrow tool windows. A new
        <b>Settings ▾</b> toggle collapses the secondary row (<i>Reload on
        save</i>, <i>Auto-refresh</i>, <i>Zoom</i>, <i>Open in</i>) into a
        single line that hides by default, and remembers your choice
        between sessions.</p>
        <p><b>Auto-refresh dropdown.</b> The auto-refresh interval is now a
        compact dropdown of presets (1, 2, 3, 5, 10, 30, and 60 seconds)
        instead of a free-form number field, freeing up room in the toolbar.
        Any previously configured interval is rounded to the nearest preset.</p>
        <p><b>Fixes.</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li><i>View Page Source</i> from the right-click menu now works.</li>
            <li>Placeholder and blank tabs are labelled <i>New Tab</i>
            instead of an internal identifier.</li>
            <li>Removed a stray bright frame that could appear around tab
            content under some themes.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.2.7</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Renamed the plugin to <b>Web Browser Panel</b> to avoid a
            Marketplace name collision. Plugin id, settings, and behaviour are
            unchanged.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.2.6</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Smart address bar:</b> typing a search phrase (e.g.
            <code>what is rust</code>) and pressing Enter now runs a
            <a href="https://www.startpage.com/">Startpage</a> search instead of
            trying to load it as a URL. URL-like inputs (with a scheme, a
            <code>/</code>, a dot, <code>localhost</code>, an IP, or
            <code>host:port</code>) still load normally. The same routing
            applies when you use <b>Open in&hellip;</b>.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.2.5</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Fix (real one): minimal pages no longer render dark.</b>
            The previous 0.2.4 attempt set <code>color-scheme: light</code>
            via JS after the page rendered, which Chromium ignored for the
            already-painted canvas. The browser's Swing wrapper is now forced
            opaque white, and untheme pages additionally get a white
            <code>body</code> background. Pages that opt into a color scheme
            of their own (<code>color-scheme: dark</code> / <code>dark light</code>)
            are still left alone.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.2.4</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Fix: dark canvas on minimal pages.</b> The embedded JCEF
            browser used to inherit the IDE's dark theme as its canvas, so
            pages that didn't declare a <code>color-scheme</code> (a minimal
            Astro/Vite starter, a stripped-down HTML page, …) rendered dark
            text on a dark background and were unreadable. The plugin now
            sets <code>color-scheme: light</code> on the root element of any
            page that doesn't opt into a scheme of its own; pages that
            intentionally support dark mode (<code>dark</code> or
            <code>dark light</code>) are left alone.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.2.3</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Brighter tool-window stripe icon on dark themes (added a
            <code>_dark.svg</code> variant using the standard IntelliJ icon
            foreground so it no longer reads as washed-out next to the
            platform's own icons).</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.2.2</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Fix: "Open browser on run" now actually fires.</b> The
            <code>ExecutionListener</code> was registered as a project listener even
            though the topic is application-level, so on recent IDE builds it
            silently never received <code>processStarted</code> events. Now
            registered as an application listener.</li>
            <li><b>Robust port probing.</b> The "wait until URL is reachable" mode
            now walks every resolved IP for the hostname (matters on macOS where
            <code>localhost</code> can resolve to <code>::1</code> first while many
            dev servers bind only to <code>127.0.0.1</code>).</li>
            <li><b>UI:</b> the address bar is now on its own line below the
            navigation buttons, so it no longer disappears when the tool window
            gets narrow.</li>
            <li>Added INFO-level logging in the open-on-run flow so future
            "nothing happened" investigations leave a trail in <code>idea.log</code>.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.2.1</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Friendlier load-failure view:</b> when a page fails to load, the
            embedded view falls back to the same themed home page shown on first
            open &mdash; no more cryptic browser error messages or assumptions about
            what kind of site you're loading.</li>
            <li>Subtle pulse animation on the home-page globe for a touch of life.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.2.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>New &mdash; Open in&hellip;:</b> a dropdown to open the current page in the system default browser or any IDE-configured browser.</li>
            <li><b>New &mdash; Open browser on run:</b> automatically open the tool window when a run configuration starts, waiting until the URL is reachable.</li>
            <li><b>New &mdash; Live reload:</b> reload on file save (selectable folder &amp; extensions) plus timed auto-refresh.</li>
            <li><b>New &mdash; Themed empty state:</b> a themed SVG placeholder in place of Chromium's error page.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3>0.1.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Initial release: embedded Chromium browser tool window with an address bar, navigation, and a configurable home URL.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <toolWindow
            id="Web Browser"
            anchor="right"
            icon="/icons/webbrowser.svg"
            factoryClass="no.dervis.webbrowser.ui.WebBrowserToolWindowFactory"/>

        <projectConfigurable
            parentId="tools"
            id="no.dervis.webbrowser.settings"
            displayName="Web Browser Panel"
            instance="no.dervis.webbrowser.ui.WebBrowserConfigurable"/>
    </extensions>

    <!-- ExecutionManager.EXECUTION_TOPIC is @Topic.AppLevel — register as an
         application listener so it actually fires across all projects. -->
    <applicationListeners>
        <listener
            class="no.dervis.webbrowser.execution.WebBrowserExecutionListener"
            topic="com.intellij.execution.ExecutionListener"/>
    </applicationListeners>

    <actions>
        <action
            id="no.dervis.webbrowser.action.OpenInWebBrowserPanel"
            class="no.dervis.webbrowser.action.OpenInWebBrowserPanelAction"
            text="Open URL in Web Browser Panel"
            description="Open the URL under the caret (or the selected text) in the Web Browser Panel tool window">
            <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="control shift B"/>
            <keyboard-shortcut keymap="Mac OS X" first-keystroke="meta shift B"/>
            <keyboard-shortcut keymap="Mac OS X 10.5+" first-keystroke="meta shift B"/>
            <add-to-group group-id="EditorPopupMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
